Kourosh Ataei

Software Engineer

https://www.mrkatae.ir
https://github.com/mrkataei
https://www.linkedin.com/in/kourosh-ataei-14a2191b8

+989036928421

<u>kouroshinfo96@gmail.com</u> Iran - Tehran

I learned all of my big major of these skills independently although I am team player and I willing to teamwork. I am flexible, punctual, diligent, ethical, loyal and accountable at work and learn quickly. Learning new languages and frameworks enable me to research and develop more and more.

Experience

Social security organization IT engineer

Feb 2023- Now

- System Administration: Managing and maintaining computer systems, networks, servers, and software applications .
- Troubleshooting and Technical Support: Identifying and resolving hardware and software issues, providing technical assistance to end-users.
- Network Infrastructure: Designing, implementing, and maintaining network infrastructure, including routers, switches, firewalls, and VPNs.
- Security Management: Implementing security measures to protect computer systems, networks, and data from unauthorized access, viruses, and other threats.

<u>Angizeh Negar (Lagrange) Backend Developer</u>

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

• Developed the backend using Python. utilizing the following Technologies: FastAPI for building efficient and scalable web APIs, SQLAlchemy ORM for managing and interacting with relational databases, Airflow for orchestrating and scheduling data workflow, Conducted data mining activities to extract valuable insights and patterns from large datasets.

AI Trader startup (Aran Accelerator) Junior Software Engineer, Co-Founder

Jun 2021 - Feb 2022

- Developed backend using Python, Utilized Django Rest Framework (DRF) for building RESTful APIs.
- Employed Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) with MySQL for efficient data management.
- Created a Telegram bot to enhance front-end functionalities.
- Served as a SysAdmin, ensuring smooth operation and maintenance of systems.
- Assumed the role of Product Manager, overseeing the following: Coordinated product development processes and collaborated with cross-functional teams. Defined product requirements, prioritized tasks, and managed project timelines.

<u>Cloud GPU Startup (Aran Accelerator) R&D Developer</u>

Dec 2020 - Jun 2021

- Configured render farm with multi-GPUs for improved performance.
- Served as a SysAdmin, ensuring smooth operation and maintenance of systems.
- Worked with PostgreSQL for efficient data management.

<u>Part software Swift Developer Intern</u>

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

- Developed iOS applications using Swift and Objective-C.
- Utilized Xcode as the primary development environment.

Selected Projects

ChatGPT Telegram bot

March 2023 - Present

• Development of a Telegram bot that uses OpenAI API to facilitate users' use of GPT chat. This bot provides facilities such as transcription and translation and chatbot.

<u>Cryptocurrency bot</u>

Dec. 2021 - Present

- Development of a Telegram bot to provide several types of strategies and automatic trading systems for customers with purchase plans.
- · Based on SQLAlchemy and Telegram API.

Optimization on TF-IDF recommender system

Fall 2020

- Basics of information retrieval and websearch, Prof.F.Ensan, FUM.
- Implemented an optimization on classical TF-IDF algorithm and proposed adaptive weight of position of word algorithm based on TF-IDF.

<u>Charity</u> Fall 2019

- Principles of Database Design, Prof.B.behkamal, FUM.
- Implementation of a free food distribution web application for charities and restaurants based on PHP and MySQL.

Roommie Nov 2022 - Present

• A web application for finding roommates. Based on the Django Rest Framework and React. This program caters to the needs of those looking for a roommate within their desired budget.

Check for more...(https://github.com/mrkataei?tab=repositories)

Education

Ferdowsi university of Mashhad

Sep 2016 - Sep 2021

- Bachelor of Computer Engineering
- GPA 15.56/20 (3.31 GPA) Last 2 years GPA is 16.59 (3.52 GPA)

Skills

- Python
- Django
- Fast API, DRF, Flask
- Java, JavaFX, Java EE
- React.js, Next.js
- Html, Css, Javascript

- Git, Docker
- SOLID, PEP8, OOP, MVC, Design Patterns
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, ORM
- Linux LPIC1
- Problem Solving
- Software Development Life Cycle

References

Dr.saeid Abrishami

Associate Professor Departement of Computer Engineering s-abrishami@um.ac.ir Professor of Artificial Intelligence

Saeid Bahmani sangesari

Graduate Research Assistant Canadian Institute for Cybersecurity saeid.bahmanisangesari@unb.ca Colleague

Dr. Behshid Behkamal

Assistant Professor Departement of Computer Engineering behkamal@um.ac.ir Professor of Data Mining

Afshin Shahrestani

Graduate Research Assistant University of British Columbia afshin.shahrestani@ubc.ca Colleague